

mrh258@live.se | 0763448444 | Askebykroken 6, Spånga, 163 70 |

Summary

Talented web and video editor with 4 years of experience. I have good knowledge of HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap as well as work experience with Adobe Illustrator, WordPress, WooCommerce, and MS Clipchamp (video) editing tools. My long experience in the graphic industry has given me a great advantage as a front-end developer and web editor. My rich language skills are an added advantage when it comes to working with clients and in an international environment.

Experience -

FOLKBRO AB | Kista, Stockhom **Web Content Manager** 06/2023 - 12/2023

- Developed and implemented web content strategies to ensure effective communication and presentation of information.
- Created (content and format) more than 10 commercial videos for company websites and digital marketing.
- Reviewed existing web content for accuracy, relevance, timeliness, completeness, and consistency in style and formatting.

TULIP REKLAM (4R PRODUCTION HB) | Kista, Sweden Executive Director 02/2009 - 05/2023

- TULIP REKLAM (4R PRODUCTION HB) | Developed graphics, logos, and layouts for product illustrations, company logos, and websites.
 - Managed multiple projects simultaneously while meeting tight deadlines.
 - Designed print materials such as brochures, flyers and posters for marketing campaigns.
- NRJ REKLAM SIA | Riga, Latvia **Advertising Manager** 01/2003 - 08/2008
- Collaborated with creative teams on the development of advertising materials.
- Organized and managed multiple projects simultaneously while meeting deadlines.
- Worked closely with clients to develop effective ad copy that meets their needs.

Education and Training

THE APP BREWERY | London, UK

THE COMPLETE WEB DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP (ONLINE COURSE)

Expected in 06/2024

• Completed coursework in HTML, Advanced CSS, Bootstrap

ABF VUXENUTBILDNING STOCKHOLM | Stockholm, Sweden SWEDISH AS A SECOND LANGUAGE (SAS) in Swedish

• Completed coursework in Swedish reading, writing and spoken at advanced high school level.

RIGA AVIATION UNIVERSITY | Riga, Latvia

BSC IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

05/1995

• Completed coursework in basic programming languages (Basic, Assembler, C++ etc.), electronics and radio electronics, computer networking etc.

• Major in Computer networking

TBILISI STATE UNIVERSITY (GEORGIA) | Tbilisi, Georgia RUSSIAN AS A SECOND LANGUAGE in Russian Studies 06/1991

• Completed continuing education in the Russian language medium at the University level.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Coding HTML, CSS, Bootstrap
- Graphics Adobe Illustrator
- CMS Word Press
- CRM Bitrix24
- Microsoft Office
- Google docs
- Digital & Offset printing
- Packaging design & production

Languages

Bengali: First Language

English:	C2	Russian:	C1
Proficient (C2)		Advanced (C1)	
Swedish:	B2	Arabic:	B1
Upper Intermediate (B2)		Intermediate (B1)	
Latvian:	B1	Urdu:	A2
Intermediate (B1)		Elementary (A2)	
Hindi:	A1		
Beginner (A1)			

Personal Information

- Title: Front End Web developer
- Date of Birth: 10/21/72
- Nationality: Swedish, Bangladeshi
- Driving License: B (Swedish)

Hobbies and Interests -

- Traveling
- Training
- Sports (Volleyball, badminton, table tennis, chess, etc.)

References

References available upon request.